<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<!-- edited with XMLSpy v2005 rel. 3 U (http://www.altova.com) by  () -->
<!-- edited with XMLSPY v2004 rel. 2 U (http://www.xmlspy.com) by XMLSPY 2004 Professional Ed. Release 2, Installed Multi + SMP for 3 users (Firaxis Games) -->
<!-- Sid Meier's Civilization 4 -->
<!-- Copyright Firaxis Games 2005 -->
<!-- -->
<!-- Concepts for the Civilopedia -->
<Civ4GameText xmlns="http://www.firaxis.com">
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CONCEPT_REVOLUTION_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[H1]Revolution[\H1][PARAGRAPH:2]A "revolution" occurs when you change your civilization's [LINK=CONCEPT_CIVICS]Civics[\LINK] or [LINK=CONCEPT_RELIGION]Religion[\LINK].[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Effects of a Revolution[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]During a revolution your civilization descends into one or more turns of "anarchy." A civilization in anarchy produces no food, commerce, or production! Any progress towards completing buildings, units, or projects is stopped until the revolution is over.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Duration of a Revolution[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]The duration of a revolt depends upon the number of civics that you change: one or two civics will usually result in one turn of anarchy, while three or more civics may cause two or more turns of anarchy. The civics screen tells you how many turns of anarchy you may look forward to after you choose which civics to change. If the length of time is too long, either make fewer changes or cancel them altogether until you can spare the time. Religions always have one turn of revolution.[NEWLINE][TAB]In Realism Invictus, the maximum anarchy from a single revolution is 3 turns, unless you have specific traits.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Immunity to Revolution[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]Civilizations with [LINK=CONCEPT_LEADERS]Leaders[\LINK] possessing the "Spiritual" trait do not suffer the effects of revolution or anarchy at all.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Delay Period[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]After a revolution has taken place, there is a short period of delay before another revolution can be carried out. When the "Revolution" button appears once again on the civics screen, your citizens have recovered enough from the previous anarchy to carry out another revolution.[PARAGRAPH:2]</English>
		<German>[H1]Revolution[\H1][PARAGRAPH:2]Wechseln Sie die [LINK=CONCEPT_CIVICS]Staatsform[\LINK] oder die [LINK=CONCEPT_RELIGION]Religion[\LINK] Ihrer Zivilisation, kommt es zur Revolution.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Folgen einer Revolution[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]Nach dem Wechsel der Staatsform versinkt Ihre Zivilisation einige Runden lang in Anarchie. W&#228;hrend dieser Zeit regiert das Chaos: Ihre B&#252;rger produzieren keine Nahrung mehr, bauen keine Ressourcen ab und stellen die Produktion ein.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Dauer der Revolution[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]Die Dauer einer Revolution h&#228;ngt von der Zahl der ge&#228;nderten Staatsformen ab. Wechseln Sie eine oder zwei Staatsformen, dauert die Anarchie nur eine Runde. Wechseln Sie aber drei oder mehr Staatsformen, kann die Phase der Anarchie zwei oder mehr Runden umfassen. Im Staatsformen-Bildschirm wird die Dauer der Anarchie im Falle des Wechsels einer Staatsform angezeigt. Dauert Ihnen die Anarchie zu lange, sollten Sie weniger Staatsformen wechseln oder den Wechsel auf einen sp&#228;teren Zeitpunkt verschieben. &#196;ndern Sie die Religion, dauert die Revolution grunds&#228;tzlich eine Runde.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Immunit&#228;t[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]Zivilisationen mit spirituellen [LINK=CONCEPT_LEADERS]Staatsoberh&#228;uptern[\LINK] haben auch nach dem Wechsel der Staatform keine Revolution zu bef&#252;rchten.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Verz&#246;gerungsphase[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]Nach dem Wechsel der Staatsform m&#252;ssen Sie daher einige Runden warten, bevor Sie die Staatsform erneut &#228;ndern k&#246;nnen. Wird der Revolution-Button im Staatsformen-Bildschirm wieder angezeigt, haben sich Ihre B&#252;rger erholt und sind bereit f&#252;r die n&#228;chste Revolution.[PARAGRAPH:2]</German>
	</TEXT>
</Civ4GameText>